A Guide to the Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #2411
Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy Papers 1920-1938
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
2411
ca. 55 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1945 November 13
Container List
- Manuscripts
  - "The Young Elizabeth" ["The Crown of Flame"] by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Alice Kauser copy, 1920 Sep; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" ["The Crown of Flame"] by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Alice Kauser copy, 1920; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" ["The Crown of Flame"] by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Curtis Brown, Ltd. copy, 1921 Nov; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" ["The Crown of Flame"] by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Author's copy, 1925; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Original Cutting without re-writes and revisions of Act IV, 1926; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Brandt & Brandt copy, 1927 Oct; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: with autograph revisions by the author, 1934 Dec; TMsS (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Brandt & Brandt copy, 1934 Dec; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Brandt & Brandt copy with re-writes and revisions, 1936; TMs (Box Box 1)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1937 May; TMss (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: with autograph re-writes but not corrected, 1938 Feb; TMs (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: script with autograph re-writes and revisions as well as stage directions, 1938 June; TMsS (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Brandt & Brandt copy corrected by the author, 1938 July; TMsS (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: re-writes of Acts III and IV, 1927-1938 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: re-writes of Act IV, 1927 Oct (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: re-writes of Act IV, 1934 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Photographs of Little Theatre of St. Louis Production, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - "The Young Elizabeth" by Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy: Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - A. W. Barmby to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1922 (Box Box 2)
  - Harold Bassage to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1937-1938 (Box Box 2)
  - Carl Brandt to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1937-1938 (Box Box 2)
  - Harry Clemons to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1938 (Box Box 2)
  - Janet Cohn to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1938 (Box Box 2)
  - Bernard M. L. Ernst to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1928, 1937 (Box Box 2)
  - Harley Granville-Barker to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1919-1922 (Box Box 2)
  - Helen Granville-Barker to Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy, 1926 (Box Box 2)